It's good to be here. Good to be in the
weather.
Uh don't get to experience it much um as
we meet, you know, every day and then we
get back Wednesday and we have draft
meetings. So, pretty exciting stuff. Uh
happy to take your questions.
>> George, can you just walk us through the
the Waddle deal and how it came over?
>> Yeah, I mean,
you know, we had an interest at the
trade deadline. I think everyone knows
that. Um it didn't get very far then.
Um but we still like the player a lot.
Uh got through our off-season process
with our roster and then free agent
meetings and and uh
and really it was just kind of still out
there. You know, at the combine we
hadn't talked yet. And then when we got
back to the combine, uh reached out um
to John Eric and then it kind of started
from there and and obviously did a lot
of work on him. All the coaches did,
scouts. Um we'd done a lot of work at
the trade deadline.
Um we felt like we knew the player well.
We knew the person um even better. And
so feel really good about the trade.
George, what what does he bring to this
team?
Well, he's one of the more ex- you know,
explosive playmakers in the league first
and foremost. Um great makeup, great
competitor. He'll fit in well with our
room. Uh we really like our room. I've
said that uh on a number of, you know,
Courtland and Pat Bryant and Troy and
and Mimsy. So, we have a great room and
he just upgrades or he just helps the
room and uh opens up the run game. He'll
open it up for the other receivers.
Um so, we think he'll fit in well with
the group.
>> George, how does this kind of change
your draft strategy? I mean, obviously
don't have the first round or lower
rounder. How does that all affect
Well, obviously we're focused on the 30
in the second. You know, we've been
fortunately been there before. I think
two different times and so we have a
good feel for that and we can we can
hone in. Doesn't mean we won't trade up
at some point, but we'll have a really
good feel for, you know, the 62nd pick
or whatever we're picking. You know, we
took a Mims at 64, you know, Bonitto 64.
We have a pretty Harvey maybe 60, I
think. So, we have a pretty good feel um
you know, of that realm. George, when
you say you like the room, is there any
consideration now to to moving any
pieces that you have in the receiver
>> No, we really like those pieces and
they're all going to help us. They've
they've all helped us up to now. I'm
going a little Jordan and and Bandy. I
mean, we we really like we're seven
eight deep. We really like it and so why
would we
you know, build up this room then then
trade someone right now? When you have a
when when you when you're talking about
dealing a first round pick and plus
obviously that's that's steep or is a
lot. So, when you like just what goes
into that conversation and does the
caliber of the class or sort of what it
looks like at 30, Well, you do look at
that. You look at the caliber of the
free agent class. You look at the
caliber of the draft class. Who can we
get at 30 within the draft class?
[music] Then you factor in
the cap and the finances, you know, not
just this year but down the road. The
fact that he's 27 years old, uh the fact
that it was 30, it wasn't 16. Uh we
compared it to all the other trades the
last 10 years of with a first round pick
and and the the value we felt, you know,
was 26. That's the the value we we gave
him and and so you look into all that
when you make a trade like this. I mean,
I
no one loves picks more than me. So,
that that's hard and I've
probably traded too many, god darn it,
but uh
but I think it's worked out.
>> George, how how close were you to
getting a deal done at the trade
deadline? You mentioned that there I
wouldn't say it was real close, you
know, I think uh
they kind of stuck to their guns. I give
them a lot of credit um
and and and really John Eric, you know,
and first time GM, I mean, total pro the
way he handled everything. Um so, it
worked out.
>> Was there anything that kind kind of
changing your thinking in terms of
sacrificing draft capital between
late October and this point based on
>> You know, you kind of know where you we
you know, we know it's 30 now, you know,
in in in late October you know, we
didn't know where it would be. We again,
we were healthy at receiver. You know,
we we we were unhealthy towards the end
of the season and so we liked our group.
We I mean, we were on a win streak, you
know, we were we were rolling pretty
good and the and it was high. I mean,
they were asking a lot at that time and
then the more you think about it, the
more you go through all your different
models, like I said, cap and and draft
picks, who's available in the draft,
free agency, all that. Um who could
really help us, you know, our team.
It it had to be a unique circumstance
for us to do this to make a trade like
this and we just felt this was too
unique to pass up.
>> George, could you take us through your
the conversation with PS2 when you let
him know that his uh college roommate
was coming back?
>> Well, I he knew. Like I called him
um and I talked to Pat about him a lot
at the trade at the trade deadline. I
didn't talk to him before this and um
but I did call him, attempted to get a
hold of him and he called me right back.
I mean, he was he was screaming. He was
very happy. That's his guy as you know.
In free agency, can you talk about
prioritizing your own guys Right.
>> lot of the outside? Well, I mean, uh
yep and I think you kept tally. How what
do we have?
We got the first tally.
>> it was 17.
>> 17. We like our players. I mean, that
was the plan. We we compare all our
players to what's there in free agency
and our guys favored, you know, where
they were pretty high and then we won a
lot of games with these guys. They fit
the culture and not everyone does.
Hard working good I mean, you're talking
Singleton and Strnad and JK Dobbins.
They really changed the landscape of our
offense and Trout and and those type of
guys.
And then you kind of look it's just an
extension of what we've done over the
last year and a half. You know, we had
10 extensions and these are some of the
best players in the league. Surtain,
Meinerz, Bonitto, Zach Allen, Roach. I
mean, Court, Bolles, all these guys. And
so, you can't do that and then make a
big splash like some of these teams do.
And so, we feel really good with what we
accomplished in free agency. We filled a
lot of needs with good players that we
know and yet we had flexibility to go
make a trade. And so,
if we didn't if we just jumped out and
made a big splash to trade, we wouldn't
been able to make the trade. Can you
specifically
address the decision at inside
linebacker holding on to Singleton and
Strnad and then letting Greenlaw go?
Well, we just we
I mean, Singleton and Strnad are just
really good players and Dre we couldn't
keep the three of them. Uh Dre helped us
win, you know, a bunch of games. He
helped our culture. We wish him the
best, but uh we're really happy to have
Strnad and Singleton. With JK, kind of
how do you kind of balance like what he
brought versus also the fact that
unfortunately he's landed on IR each
year? No, you're right. It's it's a
tough balance, but um he's 27 years old.
He's completely healthy now. Um that
injury was kind of a it was a hip drop,
you know, it was a freak. His body
didn't break down. He could have played
in the Super Bowl.
Um
this guy from the minute he walked in
our building changed it. And so, it's
like you know, we just didn't want to
let him leave. You know, he meant too
much to the building. He's a he was a
top four rusher in the league when he
got hurt. Um let's sign him back. You
know, he meant too much to this team.
George, I think last year you
signed him for over 84% on roster
retention. It was the number one in the
league.
And I'd be willing to bet you got to be
right around there if not higher. What I
think How unique is that and what's that
kind of say about where y'all are?
>> Yeah, I haven't done the studies on
that. I know it's probably pretty
unique, you know, especially this year.
I think uh
it's not for everyone what what we're
doing, you know, in the culture and and
man, the guys we have, you know, really
fit it. Um
it just it's kind of worked out that
way, you know, um
it's hard to get deals done in free
agency. We're able to get deals done
with our guys and we're glad to have
them here. Time for a few more for
George. With with JK though, just the
the injury history, are you comfortable
with the backs that you have there? Are
you looking We are. We like the we like
the backs. Um
um RJ's just going to keep getting
better.
What do you have? 12 touchdowns?
Explosive play I mean, explosive
receiver out of the backfield. Matchup
problem. He's going to get better as a
runner. He got better as the year went
on. Then you got Badey, you got Jaleel.
Uh we got Cody Schrader we like. We're
going to be looking in the draft. We're
going to be looking after the draft.
We're always looking. I mean, we didn't
sign JK till what? May or June last
year. So, we feel good with where we're
at right now. I mean, last year at this
time
we didn't have JK and we didn't have RJ
and
you know, we were we were we were okay,
you know. So, we'll we're going to be
fine. Tiden, do you feel
How do you kind of reset from last year
and then start over? Obviously made it
all the way to AFC Championship.
>> Yeah.
Kind of go all the way back to square
one like Sean talks about. How difficult
is is that to do?
It's not difficult at all. It's what we
do. We start over and uh and it starts
the day after the season as you get
through all your evaluations and free
agency and the draft and then once you
get in the off-season program, I mean,
you start over and the players know that
and it's it's you just don't show up
with a you know, 14 14 wins. You know,
you got to start over and and Sean
obviously will emphasize that.
As you're going through the the sort of
first opening days of free agency, how
much once JFM signed the deal in
Tennessee, like how much does the idea
of having a pretty good comp pick in 27
sort of factor into what you do you
know, down
>> Yeah, it does. I mean, it doesn't
dictate what kind of what we're doing,
but we obviously know it's there. We we
got, you know, two compensatory picks
this year. Uh Mr. Irrelevant, Pat's
really happy about that all in the
media. And then we have Mr. Irrelevant
runner up. So, it'll be cool. He'll be
working a lot after the draft. And then
next year we're you know, we should get
the four and maybe a seven. That's what
you That's what you want to get to. It
took us a while to get here, you know,
where we can get compensatory picks and
and you see other teams do it and and
I'm I'm I like that we're doing it.
George, you talk about talk talk about
talk about those picks, but how valuable
can those chips be especially you're
negotiating with guys in round seven and
maybe you don't know if you can get them
as undrafted guys.
>> It's great. It's great because you may
not be able to get a guy he's he's, you
know, the price gets higher sometimes
than the picks, you know, um in the free
agent world. It's crazy the chaos and
and so if we're not going to get a guy,
we you know, that happened with Jonathan
Cooper, believe it or not. He's going to
go to Jacksonville with Urban Meyer.
Let's just take him, you know, rather
let him walk out and we took him. And
so, those sevens, I mean, I mean, we got
Valery in the seventh, we got Cooper in
the seventh. I mean, there's probably
more, but um they're very I mean, all
those picks are important. George,
what kind of Bo's reaction is to adding
a playmaker like Waddle and his
I mean, yeah, I wasn't with him when he
found out, but he was pretty excited
when I walked down to the training room.
He was excited. Obviously went to dinner
with all of us. Um
you know, Bo both I think thinks he's
kind of a quasi GM sometimes and uh
sometimes he's right, sometimes he's
wrong. I think he's right on this guy.
Um this guy's pretty special. Well, I
saw they were at the Nuggets game last
night. I mean, we we get the Bo's kind
of in town all the time.
But to have Waddle there with him and
you know, Mims and whoever the guys are
there now. Yeah.
No, it's great. You know, our plot
are in house. A lot of our players are
working out. I mean, they're staying in
Denver. It's a close-knit group. It's a
tight group.
And and you see it on the field. You see
it translate. And you guys have been
around our our locker room and our
practice how close
that team was last year in the locker
room on the field. It showed late in
games.
It's hard to replicate that, but you
know, it's good that they're starting
starting Last one, Luka. leaving, was
there more of the thought, "Hey, we want
to replace this guy externally?" Or are
you like kind of the room internally?
>> Well,
Yeah, I mean, just going into it, we
feel pretty good. We have Savion, you
know, we have our four guys coming back,
you know, and
our starters and then any really came
on. Then Savion and and Jordan Jackson.
So, we have a pretty good depth, but you
know, you're always looking for big
guys, you know, in the offense and
defense lines.